yeah i was told because i feel like it's
going to hold that
muscle yeah this is good now here's the
super important thing i got to got you
this racket babylon pure drive it's a
light so it's 270 grams i believe let me
check
i think it's 270. so the racket you had
before was yeah 270. the racket before
was maybe around the same same weight
but this one is a little bit stiffer
it's going to give you more power and i
strung it super loose with a really
elastic polyester string i think what's
gonna happen is you are feel more power
and you're gonna have to exert less
effort it's gonna be easier on your arm
i haven't played for like two the last
time we played was that lesson when you
have that bad pain
and it's been how long two and a half
months ago right
forehand is looking good
i want to show you some exercises that
can help your tennis elbow
no i did i did a lot of research i
contacted some doctor students of mine
and a couple of chiropractors that i
teach we're gonna do the best treatment
available for tennis elbow okay can't
wait put this on your lap like this put
your arm here and just start massaging
your arm
with a piece of ice like this take a
piece of ice and just rub it on the spot
where it hurts
you can do it like before you play and
you can do it at night you're gonna put
your arm like this okay you're gonna
take your and i would take the band off
take your sweat yeah take the right
sweat pan off
and now
see the muscles and the fibers go this
in this direction so you're gonna go
against you're gonna start massaging in
this direction just start massaging with
your fingers this way
and do it hard like you can go deep it's
massaging on the spot where it hurts
like really hard but going across the
arm like that yeah i feel like you feel
that strings
oh yeah exactly
exactly this is going to help you a lot
again this is something that you can do
every single day okay so there's the
first stage you're gonna massage the arm
now the second stage you're gonna you're
gonna stretch it a little bit stretch
yeah and the first thing you're gonna do
is i have a board here and you can do
this on a table or
you get a cutting board like this and
you're going to pull on the hand like
this so put this board on your lap
place your forearm there and just put
the hand backwards like this
and just do it a few times and hold it
now you you flex the arm like this and
you pull it this way you help you help
push against your hand backwards like
this there you go you feel that yeah
that's it
perfect okay so you do that now the
third step is you're going to do some
strength exercises and the first one
again you're going to put your arm on a
cutting board you're going to go down
like this and you're simply going to go
up like that
like this
down and up make sure you go down slowly
like that do that
about 10 times perfect
okay that's something you can do and now
we're gonna
you do like to like do like two sets of
ten three sets of ten and now we're
gonna put this under your foot put your
foot through here the other way put your
hand the other way and i'll do the same
thing go down with the wrist and up also
a little bit yeah but make sure you go
down slowly
okay down slowly
there you go and then do the same fibers
i feel like working absolutely 100
you do that you want to massage them and
release them and also work out at the
same time
well i think you should start you should
start with a massage and you should
loosen it up a little bit warm it up a
little bit and then do some strength
exercises
how does that feel
just i think i can do it with a free
weight too maybe you could you could but
this is good because it gives you the
resistance the whole way with the weight
you have to be careful when you go down
not to go down to don't go down too fast
with the weights
like that
here's what you're gonna do you're gonna
you can do this against the door or
anything make sure the arm goes on the
inside of this okay so that you can push
this way you want to push your arm on
the inside with your left hand inwards
this way okay and now you're going to
start making a few push on here you
start making a fist like this okay you
do this 10 times you can even do
different angles you can go down you go
like this you push on it and it's going
to feel like a big time relief it's
going to feel really good put your arm
put your arms in here
and i'll push here like this push it
with your left arm
stand a little bit more this way there
you go
push against here and i start making a
fist make a fist you go a little bit
more forward like this and i'll push
against the arm
you feel that yeah okay and i'll change
the angle you go down a little bit
okay perfect
there you go nice job trouble yes
you are in trouble you know what from
delaware beach people were like yeah uh
coach jeff texted me like anna i saw
your videos
about serving about serve oh yeah
oh wow you're so good you know we i i
don't think jeff ever saw me on this
video he saw you for the first time
without you telling him yeah that's cool
i started being aware i started carrying
things in my left hand more oh yeah and
stopped holding my phone like this and
it helped you
well i'm more aware of what might
potentially hurt me you know yes and i
think it's important to bring up two
people you know of course chinese
players
how many hours do you spend a day on the
phone
i don't know not much not that much
yeah but i'm afraid like my bones here
just uh talk to me and just ignore what
i'm doing
are you hungry by any means
you want to have a can of beans no no
you don't like beans no what are you
doing just don't worry about it
no don't worry about it
the most ridiculous things in the world
this is the best tennis elbow exercise
in the world this is one are you gonna
give this to me to go no no no it's too
dangerous to make myself you have to
make it yourself no
okay this is perfect
of course i am here right here
maybe the best exercise of all time for
tennis elbow because a lot of the things
that we did for strength was just kind
of extending the hand and working on
these muscles
to protect the tennis elbow so here
watch this here's the can of beans of
course for me it should be a little bit
longer and now we're going to turn it
like this
until the can is
all the way up
to the top
okay and then once you reach the top you
turn it back the other way
so you're working both ways you're
working on wrist flexion and extension
and make sure you don't go like this and
let it roll down make sure you're you're
going like that all right go ahead and
try it keep your arms extended and i'll
start rolling
there you go
okay all the way all the way to the top
anna
all the way to the top and now back down
keep the arms more straight
more straight
music for this i know this is hard right
yeah and i go all the way down you feel
it burning in your arms
but it's a good but it's a good burn
come on all the way down on it go keep
going oh my god oh my god is it hard
right yeah if you do this every day
your tennis elbow is going to go away oh
i'm doing it all right
quick disclaimer i am not a medical
professional if you have tennis elbow
the first thing you got to do is go see
your chiropractor or your doctor the
things that we're demonstrating in this
video are things that i learned from
doctors that i teach on the court so do
not take this as medical advice if you
have tennis elbow go see your doctor is
when you start reading the comments
about this racket people are going to
tell you this racket is going to give
you tennis elbow but you just have to
yeah because it's a little bit stiffer
racket but the experience
i think that with this racket with this
combination
this weight
and the lightness of it the grip size
most importantly and the type of strings
are on here and the tension of the
strings is going to be the
tennis elbow healer this racket
but what they're going to tell you i'm
telling you right now in the comments
they're going to tell you anna don't
play with this rack it's going to give
you tennis elbow so you just got to
listen to me okay yes and of course if
you play with this rack and your arm is
absolutely killing you then we change it
again okay i'll buy you another one
good job nice on top elbows go up
good
yes
anna beautiful
good work
nice shot anna
nice job and you know what the great
thing is like you haven't played tennis
for two and a half months
but all this stuff is still there all
the most all the work that you did in
the last like year and a half it's also
there it didn't go anywhere you know so
it's not like you completely forget how
to play tennis everything's fine so in
other words it's okay to take breaks to
make sure you heal properly
okay very nice
good
yes wow
i love that backhand
oh
beautiful backhand maybe you got tennis
elbow from dancing look at this
i'm just kidding no
you want to play more
strong
come
you overheat a little too hard you have
to be a little more careful there
because you hit it way below your hip
so it's like from there from that closed
position to the net
if the ball drops below the level of
your waist if you hit hard like that
it's going to fly out you're very close
to the baseline there
you have to be a little bit more
cautious take like half 50 off the shot
and get it in match point
beautiful forehand very nice
nothing hurts
are you kidding me nothing hurts nothing
hurts you have no pain no are you
serious yeah yeah okay we're doing the
right things and we made unbelievable
changes today we changed the grip we
changed the racket we changed the
tension we still got the same strings
but we know what else now you got to
plan to make the pain go away with these
exercises
okay yeah this is great